motoguzzi.com 2015-10-28

# PRIVACY POLICY – NOTIFICATION ON THE PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA Notification pursuant to art. 13 of Legislative Decree 196/2003

         PRIVACY POLICY – NOTIFICATION ON THE PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA
                         Notification pursuant to art. 13 of Legislative Decree 196/2003
The company Piaggio & C. S.p.a. (hereinafter “Piaggio” or the “Company”), with registered offices located in
Pontedera (PI) at Via Rinaldo Piaggio n. 25, represented by the individual temporarily appointed by the Board of
Directors to handle personal information, domiciled in the company’s offices, wishes to inform you of the following.
This information is provided only for this website ( "Site") and not to other websites that may be accessed by the user
("User") via the link .
The identifying data provided by the User during the registration in the Website and/or subscription to the services,
initiatives and promotions publicized, will be used by Piaggio, and may be provided to third parties, in compliance with
the principles of data protection established by Legislative Decree 196/2003 and other applicable current legislation.
                                      Purpose of the processing of personal data
Piaggio will manage this information:
a)        for the purpose of providing the services requested, checking the quality of services offered and fulfilling all
          legal accounting and fiscal requirements;
b)        only if you specifically give your express consent, for commercial purposes, for promotions and marketing
          through online and offline channels, and for the purpose of conducting market surveys and statistical surveys
          such as monitoring customers’ satisfaction with Piaggio products and services and/or those of other companies
          in the Piaggio Group or sending technical or promotional information on products and services offered by
          Piaggio and/or by its affiliates and/or by the Piaggio Group’s dealers and/or distributors. The information may
          be provided to other companies in the Piaggio Group and/or to specialized companies (requiring them to adopt
          data security and protection criteria in line with current legislation) for the purposes for which the information
          was collected.
Giving your consent to use of your personal information for the purposes specified in point a) is optional but necessary
for accessing the services, promotions and offers announced by Piaggio on its web sites and the user’s failure to provide
this information will make it impossible for Piaggio to provide the requested service.
Giving your consent to use of your personal information for the purposes specified in point b) is optional and failure to
do so will not prevent you from accessing the services and promotions offered.
                                                        Cookie Policy
We hereby inform you regarding the use of “cookies” by Piaggio as a way to make more pleasant for the User the web
browsing experience in the Website .
A cookie is a small file that the Website transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer's hard disk so that
the website can remember who you are in order to be retransmitted to the Website at the next visit.
The cookies are used for different purposes such as: running computer authentication, session tracking, storing
information about specific configurations of users accessing the server.
Cookies allows the Website to remember User’s data for the length of the visit or the next visits, allowing the User di
web browsing among pages efficiently, storing the User’s preferences, and in order to allow the User to interact and
share content through social networks, such as Facebook, Google +, Instagram and offer Google Maps’ services
User’s data will be handled anonymously, aggregate, not persistent and will not be used for the transmission of personal
data or to send advertising, nor the systems are used for tracking and profiling of the User.
We hereby also inform you that some of the activity could not be carried out without the use of cookies ("strictly
necessary cookies”) which in some cases are technically essential
Cookies may be used to storage the login data of the User, therefore to help recognizing automatically the User (thus
making it unnecessary the login procedure every time the User access the Website)
The processing of the data will be done with the aid of electronic or in any case computerized or telematics devices,
form on the basis of processing logic strictly correlated with the purposes listed above and, in any case, to ensure the
security and confidentiality of the Data.

According to current legislation in Italy, express consent is not always required for the use of cookies. In particular, so-
called "technical" cookies, i.e. those used for the sole purpose of carrying out the transmission of a communication over
an electronic communications network, or as strictly necessary to provide a service explicitly requested by the user, do
not require such consent. These are, in other words, cookies essential for the functioning of the website or necessary to
perform tasks requested by the user.
Technical cookies
Among technical cookies, which do not require consent for their use, the Italian Authority for the Protection of Personal
Data also includes:
     • “analytics cookies” when used directly by the website manager to collect information, in aggregate form, on
          the number of users and how they visit the website,
     • browsing or session cookies (to log on, to make a purchase, etc.),
     • functionality cookies, which allow the user to browse according to a set of selected criteria (for example,
          language, the products selected for purchase) in order to improve the service rendered to the same.
Profiling cookies
For so-called profiling cookies, on the other hand, i.e. those aimed at creating profiles concerning the user and used in
order to send advertising messages in line with the preferences demonstrated by the same while surfing the net, prior
consent is required.
Third-party cookies
While web browsing on the Website, you may receive on your terminal also cookie from different sites or webserver ("
third-party cookie) on which can be located some elements (such as, for example, images, maps, sounds, specific links
to pages on other domains) on the site that the User is visiting. In this case these are cookies that are set by a website
other than the one you are currently visiting.
Delete and manage cookies
Users can select which cookies allow through the appropriate procedure provided below, as well as authorize, block or
delete (in whole or in part) cookies through the specific functions of their browser nevertheless, in the event that all or
some cookies are disabled, it is possible that the website cannot be consulted or that some services or certain functions
of the website are not available or are not working properly and/or users could be forced to change or manually enter
certain information or preferences each time they visit the website.
If you do not want your computer to receive and store cookies, you can modify the security settings of your browser,
follows brief instructions on how to do this in the four most popular browsers:
          Microsoft Internet Explorer
          Click the 'Tools' icon in the upper right corner and select 'Internet Options'. In the pop-up window select
          'Privacy'. Here you can adjust the settings of your cookies.
          Google Chrome
          Click the 'wrench' icon in the upper right corner and select 'Settings'. Then select “Under the hood" and change
          the settings in the 'Privacy' section.
          Mozilla Firefox
          From the pull-down menu in the upper left corner, select 'Options'. In the pop-up window select 'Privacy'.
          Here you can adjust the settings of your cookies.
          Safari
          From the pull-down menu in the upper right corner, select 'Preferences'. Select 'Security' and from here you
          can adjust the settings of your cookies.

As already envisaged in the banner that immediately appears when first visiting the website, consent to the use of all
cookies can be provided by users by selecting the virtual acceptance key (e.g. an OK, a tick, etc.) or by continuing to
browse the website (e.g. ignoring the banner/pop-up and performing further operations). Users will also have free
access to the extended disclosure link, complete with all cookie information (description, purpose and storage), in which
the website visitor will be able to provide consent only for certain categories of cookies.
Types of cookies:
In order to achieve proper regulation of cookies, as well as conscious expression of consent to the use or otherwise of
the same, below is some brief information on the different categories into which they are divided.
     1.    Strictly necessary cookies
          These cookies are essential to proper run the Website. These cookies include the ones that allow the User to be
          remembered when browsing in the Website during a session or, if required, from one session to another one.
          Some of the services cannot be provided without these type of cookies.
          These cookies are not used for other purposes and are usually installed by the owner or operator of the
          Website. They can be divided into browsing cookies or session cookies, which guarantee the normal browsing
          and the use of a Website (allowing, for example, to make a purchase or login to access restricted areas);
          analytics cookies, which are Strictly necessary cookies in case they are used directly by the operator of the
          Website to collect information, in aggregate form, the number of users and how they visit the Website;
          functionality cookies, which allow the User to brows with a set of selected criteria (for example: the language,
          the products selected for the purchase) in order to improve the service rendered to the User.
          In order to install these cookies is not required the prior consent of the user, while it remains subject to the
          obligation of providing the notice pursuant to article 13 of the Code, which the operator of the Website can
          provide in the modality that deems most appropriate.
         Below, the technical cookies used by the website are listed:
Third Party Cookies       Category         Purpose                                                      Privacy Policy
  Adobe	  Analytics	    Technical	      Adobe	   Analytics	   is	   a	   statistic	             https://www.adobe.com/priva
        (Adobe)           Analytical       service	   provided	   by	   Adobe	                      cy/opt-­‐out.html#4
                                           Systems,	   Inc.	   These	   cookies	   collect	  
                                           user	   behavioral	   data.	   These	  
                                           information	   are	   used	   to	   improve	  
                                           the	   web	   site	   experience.	   All	   data	  
                                           are	  collected	  in	  anonymous	  way.
Google         Analytics  Technical	      These	   cookies	   collect	   user	                     https://developers.google.co
http://www.google         Analytical       behavioral	  data.	  These	  information	                m/analytics/devguides/collecti
.com/intl/it_ALL/an                        are	   used	   to	   improve	   the	   web	   site	   on/analyticsjs/cookie-­‐usage
alytics/learn/privac                       experience.	  All	  data	  are	  collected	  in	  
y.html                                     anonymous	  way.
     2.    Profiling Cookies
          Profiling Cookies are designed to create profiles about the Users and are used in order to send advertising
          messages in line with the preferences expressed by the User during the browsing. These cookies are used to
          present matching content to the users according to their interests. These types of cookies can be used to display
          targeted advertisements or in order to manage the number of times an advertisement is displayed. Given the
          considerable invasiveness that such devices can have within the private sphere of users, the Italian and
          European legislation requires the User to be properly informed on the use of these cookies and express their
          valid consent.
         Profiling cookies require prior acquisition of informed consent by the user, pursuant to Article 23 of Italian
         Legislative Decree no. 196/2003, which the website acquires in the forms provided for by the Provision through

        the banner that appears on the first visit and through the extended disclosure that allows the user to grant or deny
        the                                              corresponding                                               consent.
        The website is not using first party profiling cookies, does not consider it appropriate to provide for the user's
        explicit consent.
     3.   Third party cookies
        While browsing the website, users may also receive cookies of different websites or web servers (third-party
        cookies) on their terminals: this happens because there may be elements on the website such as images, maps,
        sounds or specific links to the web pages of other domains that reside on servers other than that hosting the
        requested web page. These cookies are directly set by the managers of websites or servers other than the
        Website.
        In view of the fact that the owner/manager of the website does not have direct contact with any third parties, use
        of these cookies may be disabled by users via the specific option in their browser, as well as via the link to
        www.youronlinechoises.com/it/ that allows users to activate/deactivate advertising profiling cookies present on
        the Website.
        Below, the third party cookies used by the website are listed:
Third Party Cookies       Category         Purpose                                     Privacy Policy
     Doubleclick          Profiling        These cookies are used to personalize       https://www.turn.com/trust/c
                                           information and advertising materials,      onsumer-­‐opt-­‐out
                                           in line with the interests of the user, eg.
                                           according to page views.
          Turn            Profiling	      These cookies are used to personalize       http://www.google.com/polici
                                           information and advertising materials,      es/technologies/ads/
                                           in line with the interests of the user, eg.
                                           according to page views
 Facebook Exchange        Profiling	      These cookies are used to personalize       https://www.facebook.com/help/c
                                           information and advertising materials,      ookies
                                           in line with the interests of the user, eg.
                                           according to page views
        AdForm            Profiling	      These cookies are used to personalize       http://site.adform.com/privac
                                           information and advertising materials,      y-­‐policy/en/
                                           in line with the interests of the user, eg.
                                           according to page views
                                                   Data processing rules
Your data will be handled in conformity with the requirements of the law, guaranteeing full compliance with the
provisions of the law, contracts and regulations. Your data will be used in printed form and in electronic form on the
basis of processing logic strictly correlated with the purposes listed above and in such a way as to guarantee the security
and confidentiality of the data, and in all cases in compliance with the provisions of art. 31 et seq. of Legislative Decree
196/2003 and the Technical Regulations – Annex B to this decree. The data will be kept only for as long as is necessary
for the purposes for which it was collected and for the amount of time required by civil and fiscal legislation.
                                                     Data from Minor
Piaggio does not allow minors less than 14 years of age to supply personal data
In the event a minor which is at least 14 years of age but not yet 18 years of age access the Website, his personal data
will be handled by Piaggio only after previous consent from one of Your parents or from the person who is legally
responsible for the minor.
                                              Geographical Location Data

Upon previous consent of the user, the website may process geographical location data - in a discontinuous way - to
provide the services that user has requested.
                                                Transmission of the data
The individual in charge of handling the information will avail himself/herself of the assistance of other people acting
as internal managers and possibly of external contractors, or of other people appointed to process the information
Specifically, the information may be made available to employees and other people working in the company units
involved in providing the services offered by Piaggio, and to people in the companies appointed to process the data and
in charge of performing marketing and promotional activities for the individual in charge of handling personal
information.
                                                   Data subject’s rights
Art. 7 of Legislative Decree 196/2003 entitle people who provide personal information to exercise specific rights.
Specifically, you have the right to obtain conformation of the existence or non-existence of personal information on
you, even if the information has not yet been recorded, and to view the data in intelligible form. You are also entitled to
ask where the data came from, the logic and purposes of its use and how it will be used, and to ask for details
identifying the person who will be using the information, the person in charge, the national representative and the
parties/categories to whom the information may be provided or who may become aware of it as designated
representatives of the State, managers or people appointed to handle the information You may obtain deletion,
transformation into anonymous form or freezing of information on you held in violation of the law and updating,
correction or, if you have a particular interest in doing so, supplementation of the data; you are likewise entitled to
attestation that notification of these operations has been provided to all parties to whom the information has been
provided; you may object to use of the information if you have legitimate reason to do so.
                                                    Data’s Circulation
The User's personal data will not be distributed or passed on to third parties but the ones indicated herein .
                                                      Applicable law
This Privacy Policy is governed by Italian law and in particular by the Code for the Protection of Personal Data which
governs the processing of personal data - also held overseas - carried out by anyone who is domiciled or has registered
offices in Italy or using instruments located in Italy . The Code guarantees that the processing of personal data is carried
out with respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms and dignity, particularly with regard to confidentiality,
personal identity and the right to the protection of Personal Data.
                                                      Policy changes
Piaggio may amend or simply update all or part of this Privacy Policy in consideration of the amendment of the rules of
law or regulations that govern this matter and protect your rights. Changes and updates to the Privacy Policy will be
notified to users on the site’s homepage as soon adopted and will be binding once posted on the Website in this section.
We would therefore request the User to regularly access this section to verify the publication of the most recent and
updated Privacy Policy
                    Data controller, data processor and persons in charge of the processing
The Manager appointed under art. 29 of Legislative Decree 196/2003 whom users may contact at any time to exercise
their rights under art. 7 of Legislative Decree 196/2003 is the temporary manager of the Legal and Corporate
Department. Requests may be sent to Piaggio & C. S.p.a., Ufficio Legale e Societario, Viale Rinaldo Piaggio n. 25,
56025 Pontedera (PI) or sent by email to privacy@piaggio.com.
A complete list of the people in charge of handling personal information is available by sending a request by mail to
Piaggio & C. S.p.a., Ufficio Legale e Societario, Viale Rinaldo Piaggio n. 25, 56025 Pontedera (PI) or an email
to privacy@piaggio.com.
